Arun Radhakrishnan

Phone:+91 7845951015

Mail:arunkrishnan0716@gmail.com





SUMMARY

A user centric professional with 7+ years of experience in IT industry with major focus on system administration, automation, build and deployment of code on cloud by using DevOps practices. 2+ years of experience in Digital Conversion and Advanced Excel activities.

SKILLS

- Linux RHEL, Centos, Ubuntu
- Scripting Bash and YAML
- CI -Jenkins
- Containerization Docker and Kubernetes
- Cloud AWS, Azure
- SCM GitLab
- IAC- Terraform
- Monitoring Promtail, Loki, Grafana

EXPERIENCE

Senior Process Associate

Tata Consultancy Services / Chennai, IN / Dec2018 - Present

Assignment I - Client: Digital Food Initiatives - Cloud DevOps Engineer

- Implementation of DevOps tools, techniques practices as per the application's requirements.
- Manage, modify and maintain Jenkins pipelines as per developer needs.
- Ensure health monitoring and alerting by using Grafana, Promatail, Loki.
- Managing the life cycle of SSL certificates including acquisition, deployment and renewal.
- Part of Database migration activities to upgrade Postgres version from 7 to 14.
- Built and deployed Docker containers as micro services to improve apps workflow and performance.
- Automated logs backup and cron jobs using shell scripts to archive application logs.
- Deployed and maintained Kubernetes pods for our DEV and QA environments.
- Estimated pricing for AWS services and share the recommendations to monitor costs.
- Create and deploy Kubernetes clusters on cloud environments such as AWS EKS and Azure AKS.
- Performing application deployments on Kubernetes clusters.
- Managing Kubernetes storages (PV, PVC, SC) Networking (Services, Load Balancers, DNS, Ingress).
- Managing Gitlab branching strategy and user access management for projects.
- Integrating Gitlab with Sonarqube to ensure/maintain code quality and bugs of our gitlab projects.

Technologies used: AWS Services (VPC, EC2, RDS, EKS, ECR, ECS, AWS WAF, AWS shield, ALB, Auto scaling, IAM, SQS, SNS, AWS Secrets manager, Cloud watch, Cloud front, Cloud trail, Route53), Azure Cloud, GitLab, Bash, Docker, Kubernetes, Jenkins, Terraform.

Assignment II - Client: First Caribbean International Bank - System Administrator

- Worked on building the Linux servers for testing environments.
- Maintain and update software as needed in Windows server and Linux
- Tuning the servers for stakeholder's (eg. VISA, Mastercard) application installation.
- Creation and maintenance of user accounts and permission managements.
- Worked on configuring jboss and web logic application to handle E-commerce based transactions.
- Installation of patches and software packages on Linux operating system.

- Automated Linux tasks like transactions monitoring, service monitoring and files backups.
- Managed teams shift roster and trained new joiners for infrastructure support team.
- Part of red hat HA clusters configuration activity.
- Deploying service related patches in UAT, Production and DR servers.
- Worked with multiple stack holders regarding infra upgrade and migration related activities.
- Switch the network traffic to secondary server when service performs maintenance on primary servers

Technologies used: RHEL, Jboss, Citrix, Apache tomcat, Rackspace, Weblogic, Windows AD, Bash.

System Administrator

Vikatan Group / Chennai, IN / Sep2016 - Oct2018

- Backup and restore of the data.
- Monitoring of Servers in zabbix.
- User and Security Management in Linux.
- Providing data to add sales team as per their need.
- Maintain a detail report for subscription customers.
- Tracking the SIP customers to purchase the Vikatan magazines.
- Used advanced excel functions to generate spread sheets and pivot tables.
- Performed daily data queries and prepared reports on daily, Weekly and Monthly Basis.
- Worked in preparing Weekly, Fortnightly and Monthly basis E-Magazines.

Technologies used: RHEL, Windows Server, Zabbix, Excel.

Data Conversion Specialist

HTC Global Services Pvt Ltd / INDIA, IN / Dec 2014 - Sep 2016

- Nature of the job is to make sure magazines that arrive to us is divided into different articles and the detail of the article is captured accurately analyzing objects in WFMS.
- Retrieving process status from team leaders and sending the same to the Manager for review.
- Maintain a detail reports under my shift coordinator project.
- EOD projects status mailed to shift coordinator and Shift Manager.
- Hourly reports send to shift coordinator and team leaders.
- Weekly and Monthly report for team leaders Productivity, Quality and Utilized Hours

Technologies used: Ticketing tool, MS Excel

EDUCATION

- 2014 BSc Computer Science from Sri Muthukumaran Arts and Science College, Madras University.
- 2011 12th from Sekkizhar Government Boys Higher Secondary School, Kundrathur.
- 2009 10th from Sekkizhar Government Boys Higher Secondary School, Kundrathur

ACHIEVEMENTS

- Received, on the sport award 2 times in TCS for achieved automation goals.
- In TCS, I have submitted 5 PI (Process Improvement) for projects

DECLARATION

I hereby declare that the above given information is true to the best of my knowledge